在我们第19圈的前夜
On the eve of our 19th revolution,
伟大的威尔福德先生回来了
the great Mr. Wilford came out of the cold.
那是两辆火车的时代
It was the time of two Engines.
车尾不再是车尾  而是边境
The Tail no longer The Tail, but a borderland.
一个伟大比赛策略和伟大火车策略的时代
A time of great gamesmanship and great trainsmanship...
火车运行被打断
Of revolutions interrupted
新的地带上有了新的轨道
and fresh track on new terrain.
哈维  你收到了吗
Javi, do you copy?
哈维  靠
Javi? Shit.
如果你能听到我  换到备用无线电
If you can hear me, switch to backup radio.
我去连接处
I'm going to The Connector.
在有40节车厢的大爱丽丝
Hope was our only seedling
和有994节强车厢的雪国列车之间的战争里
in the war of Big Alice, 40 cars long,
希望是我们唯一的幼苗
versus Snowpiercer, 994 cars strong.
雪国列车
第二季 第一集
"双车记"
雪国列车败局已定
Snowpiercer is dead in the water.
你们必须顺从威尔福德先生的指令
You will comply with Mr. Wilford's demands
不然我们就断开  留你们在这挣扎
or we will disconnect and leave you here to flounder.
告诉威尔福德先生  雪国列车上的人
Tell Mr. Wilford the people of Snowpiercer
-绝不会投降  -你是哪位
- will never surrender. - Who are you exactly?
你刚闯进了我的后门
I'm the guy whose backdoor you just kicked in.
我们肯定可以互相迁就吧
I'm sure that we can all accommodate one another.
莱顿先生无意冒犯
Mr. Layton means no disrespect.
是的  等我们启动后我们可以讨论
Yeah, we can discuss when we're moving.
听上去很合理  艾莉克斯
That sounds reasonable, Alex.
我相信你妈妈也会同意的
Your mother would agree, I'm sure.
我们要怎么做
How do we make that happen?
把这份清单上的东西给我搞来
Bring me everything on this list.
-啤酒  -胡萝卜和黄瓜
- Beer? - Carrots and cucumbers.
我们得去拿这些东西
We have to get all this?
你们有大约12分钟时间  不然会冷到动不了
You have about 12 minutes before it's too cold to move.
只是  这些都是不值钱的东西
It's just--it's trifles.
我们别无选择
We don't have a choice.
通讯系统挂了  附属列车也是
Hardlines are down and the subtrain.
好  我们只能靠跑了
Okay, we gotta do this by runner!
从啤酒厂拿六瓶铁路工麦芽酒
From the brewery, we need six bottles Railman's Ale.
-这就去  -让开
- On it! - Make way!
谁去图书馆拿一本
From the library, somebody get a copy
达夫妮·杜穆里埃的《蝴蝶梦》
of "Rebecca" by Daphne du Maurier.
-露丝  你跟我来  -好
- Ruth, you're with me. - Yeah.
-罗切  维护秩序  -好
- Roche, hold the line. - Got it!
-农业区  -在
- Ag-Sec. - Here!
提尔  跟过去
Till, go with.
我们需要一捆胡萝卜  一根黄瓜
We need one bunch carrots, one cucumber,
六个鸡蛋  一只母鸡
six eggs, and a hen.
-母鸡  -对
- A hen? - Yep.
哈维  你能跟梅联系上吗
Javi, have you got comms with Mel?
-我们被截停了  -我知道
- We're stopped. - Yeah, I got that.
-你有她消息吗  -什么都没有  本
- Have you got comms with her? - I've got nothing, Ben
威尔福德完全控制住了雪国列车
Wilford's got complete control of Snowpiercer.
她会知道的  她会知道要用备用无线电
She'll know. She'll know to go to backup.
梅兰妮  梅兰妮  回话  这里是火车头
Melanie, Melanie, come in, this is the Engine.
外面天气很好
Beautiful day out here.
是啊  温和的零下83度
Yeah, a balmy 118 below zero.
你回车上来吧
Let's get you back aboard.
我在连接处这里  火车轴被锁住了
I'm at the connector. The arms are locked in.
梅  你不能把我们断开
Hey, Mel, you can't disconnect us.
我知道
I know.
为了甩开他我们几乎耗尽了燃料
We drained the banks too low running from him
光靠自己无法再启动
to ever get moving on our own again.
你是对的  本  我中了计
You were right, Ben. I fell for it.
如果我炸掉上行线
If I blow the uplink,
至少你们能夺回驾驶盘和生命系统
at least you get the helm and life systems back.
你有粘性炸弹  对吗
You've got a sticky charge, yeah?
嗯  但我只有一个
Yeah, but I only have one.
梅  你的防护服温度是多少
Hey, Mel, what's your suit temp?
你马上就要体温过低  梅
You'll be going hypothermic, like, now, Mel.
梅
Mel.
零下23度
Minus ten.
所有人待命  保持手的暖和
Everybody stay ready. Keep your hands warm.
出事了
Something's happening.
只是你的腿  宝贝
It's just your train legs, honey.
你之前从未经历过停车
You've never been stopped before.
不  听我说  我听见了声音
No, listen. I hear something.
所有人安静一会儿
Hey, everyone, quiet a second!
该死  有人在外面
Shit, someone's outside.
-是我们中的一员吗  -我感觉是
- You think it's one of us? - I got a hunch it is.
不管他们在干什么  希望能起效
Whatever they're doing, I hope it works.
零下24度
Minus 12.
让那些跑腿的人快点
Tell those runners to hurry it up!
快走  我这就去
Go, I'm coming.
-快点快点  -让开
- Come on, move, move, move! - Make way!
让开  让开
Move, move!
拿上这个
Get that one.
快点  我们走  快
Come on, let's go. Come on.
我冷死了
I'm freezing.
让开
Make way!
我的天
Oh, my God.
你运气不佳
You're out of luck.
不然你指望什么
What do you expect?
我们已经治疗了170位伤员
We've already treated 170 wounded.
抱歉  雪国列车上的吗啡昨天就用完了
Sorry, Snowpiercer ran out of morphine yesterday.
什么
What?
要是威尔福德先生疼痛了该怎么办
And what if Mr. Wilford is in distress back there?
头等厢瓷器  传给下一个人
First class china, just hand it off to the next guy;
他就在外面
he's right outside.
他真的还活着
He's really still alive.
单子上的最后一件物品
Yeah, the last item on the list
是威尔福德先生最爱的一瓶苏格兰威士忌
is a bottle of Mr. Wilford's favorite Scotch.
这只是个开始  安德烈
This is just the beginning, Andre.
他会夺走我们为之奋斗的一切
He's going to take everything we just fought for.
过会儿再说吧
Tell me about it later.
让开
Out of the way.
梅兰妮  已经到极限了  你知道症状的
Melanie, that's threshold. You know the signs.
你会头晕
You'll get confused.
系统中断
你会逐渐丧失运动能力
You'll start losing your motor skills.
系统中断
我没事
I'm fine.
‎系统恢复
她做到了
She's doing it.
‎系统恢复
她让我们恢复了一半控制
She's got us a hand free.
梅  你做到了
Mel, you did it.
赶紧上车
Let's get you aboard.
我还没弄完
I'm not done yet.
梅
Mel.
我的天
Oh, my God.
这个人是什么情况
What the hell happened to that guy?
梅兰妮  回复
Melanie, Melanie, come in.
该上车了
It's time to come home.
我们有的全拿过来了  发动吧
We got what we could. Now let's move.
少了什么
What's missing?
没有吗啡了  但我们有阿司匹林
There's no morphine, but we have aspirin.
我们自己做的  他知道的
We make our own, as he knows.
听着  现在已经零下29度了
Look, it's 20 below zero here.
-我们能发动了吗  -零下30度了
- Can we get moving? - It's 22.
我相信我们可以在列车发动之后再商讨这些
I'm sure we can talk about this while the train is moving.
威尔福德先生感谢你们的配合
Mr. Wilford thanks you for your cooperation.
艾莉克斯  等等  艾莉克斯...
Alex, wait, Alex--
等等
Wait!
不  不
Oh, no. No!
太好了
Yes.
我觉得这是个好的征兆
Well, I suppose that's a good sign.
露丝  他骑在我们的脖子上
Ruth, he's got his foot on our neck.
你明白吗
You get it?
我们中大多数人刚刚为民主抗争过
The majority of us just fought a war for democracy,
你需要决定你站在哪边
so you need to decide whose side you're on.
梅兰妮
Melanie.
梅兰妮  你登上列车了吗
Melanie, are you aboard this train?
梅兰妮  上火车
Melanie, get on the train.
梅兰妮  你上车了吗  请回复
Melanie, are you aboard? Come in.
梅兰妮  快上火车
Melanie, get on the train!
这里有情况
There's something here.
好像下雪了
I think it's snowing.
-她神志不清了  -梅兰妮  听我说
- She's losing it, man. - Melanie, listen to me.
现在太冷了  不会再下雪了
It's too cold to snow anymore.
立刻上车
Get aboard the train.
梅兰妮  撑住
Melanie, stay with me.
梅兰妮
Melanie.
Melanie!
不
No.
-本  如果你能听见  -我能
- Ben, if you can hear me... - Yes.
我要登上大爱丽丝
I'm boarding Big Alice.
脱下防护服  消毒全身
Strip out of the suit for disinfection.
真幽默
Very funny.
凯文
Kevin.
在这里见到你真高兴
Fancy meeting you here.
不过你是新面孔
You're new, though.
这是惩罚你丢下我们等死
That's for leaving us to die.
我知道怎么走
I know the way.
这里还剩下多少车尾人
How many Tailies we got left down here?
只有一半左右
Only about half, I figure.
有些已经有铺位了
Some have got berths already,
但大部分人只能在前车打地铺
but most are just camping out uptrain.
我们有些人不想离开
Some of us don't wanna leave.
听着  我打算这么做
Look, here's where I'm going with this.
车尾不再是车尾了
The Tail is not The Tail anymore.
而是边境  边境地区必须得到控制
It's a border, and you have to control a border,
所以我们在这里保留一支够强大的部队
so keep a force strong enough back here
守卫真正的领地
to hold the real estate.
七年来我们不断尝试离开这地方
Seven years we've been trying to get out of this place,
如今这地方终于有价值了
and now the place is finally worth something.
我们组织起来
Let's get organized.
我们应该在这里建第二道路障
I think we should build a second barricade right here.
好主意  继续巩固这区域
Yeah, good idea. Keep strengthening this area.
如果他做好了停下列车的准备
If he's prepared to stop the train,
我们必须假设他也做好了攻击的准备
we have to assume that he's prepared to attack.
我劝你不要臆断  莱顿先生
I would advise against assumptions, Mr. Layton.
如果我们不尽快和乘客们沟通
If we don't talk to the passengers soon,
流言蜚语会把我们生吞活剥的
I swear the track talk will eat us alive.
-HART通信协议恢复了  -谢谢  露丝
- HART comms back up. - Thank you, Ruth.
我在夜车开完理事会会议后
I will address the train right after a council meeting
就会立即向全车人广播
in the Nightcar immediately.
我们要在这里跟你道别了  梅兰妮
This is where we bid you goodbye, Melanie.
木星
Hey, Jupiter.
别激动  姑娘
Hey, hey. Easy, girl.
它记得你
She remembers you.
我本来还希望它会吃了你
I was half hoping she would eat you.
你的列车有调光器
Wow, your train has dimmers.
你喜欢它吗
You like her?
我们要求老爱丽丝做的  它都超额完成了
Old Alice has done everything we've asked of her and more.
但这并不是计划  对吗
Not exactly the plan, though, was it?
走近一些
Come closer.
来啊
Come on.
让我看看岁月给你留下了什么痕迹
Let's see what the years have done to you.
你在外面砍木柴的时候
Who have you got up there driving my Engine
叫谁去开我的火车了
while you're outside chopping firewood, hmm?
是本吗
Is it Ben?
名字  等级和编号
Name, rank, and serial number.
你只能知道这些
That's all you get.
抱歉
Sorry.
我太急切了
Too eager.
我没料到我们这么快就会见面  你呢
Never expected we'd come face to face so quickly. Did you?
不过的确是本  对吧
It's Ben, though, isn't it?
你总有鉴别人才的眼光
You've always had an eye for talent.
不如说说你吧  你怎么做到的
Why don't we talk about you? How'd you do it?
说吧
Come on.
你是怎么在芝加哥追上我们的
How'd you drop in on us in Chicago like that?
我知道你等不及告诉我了
I know you're dying to tell me.
是的  可算
Yes, finally.
我就喜欢霸道小说  你呢
I love a good swashbuckler, don't you?
你估计已经想明白一部分了
You've probably figured out some of it.
我让爱丽丝维持低怠速
I got Alice to low idle,
设法在一个小屋里躲避了几个月
managed to hunker down in a shed for a couple of months.
等你到了世界另一端
By the time you were on the other side of the world
卫星拍不到时  我们已备好装备
out of satellite view, we were outfitted.
我没停止过工作  梅兰妮
I was always working, Melanie,
耐心等待突袭的时机
waiting for my moment to pounce.
就是这样
Voilà.
你走了捷径吗
And, um, you took a shortcut?
是的  你是从
Yeah, you came over
老落基山脉的试验轨道过来的  对吧
the old Rocky Mountain test track, didn't you?
你把钥匙交给我  我就全告诉你
I'll tell you everything when you give me the keys.
-我不能那么做  -你会的
- Ah. I can't do that. - Oh, you will.
虽然你切断了我的上行线
You may have cut my uplink,
但我仍能抛锚  让你的列车慢慢停下来
but I can still drop anchor and grind you to a halt.
你要是断开  雪国列车20分钟都撑不了
Snowpiercer won't survive more than 20 minutes if you disconnect.
很讽刺  对吧
It's ironic, isn't it?
我的门生
My protégé.
这些年来  你都逃避我
You run away from me all these years,
突然间
and all of a sudden,
你无法忍受和我分开
you just can't bear to be apart from me.
我要拿回我的列车  梅兰妮
I want my train back, Melanie.
事实上  不久前它都还在你手中
Actually, you still ran her until very recently.
这话是什么意思
What's that supposed to mean?
意思是  我发现让你活着会比较简单
Means I found it easier to keep you alive.
我让人们相信你还在火车头
I convinced people you were still in the Engine,
但我失去控制了
but I lost control.
我无权把雪国列车交还给你
She's not mine to surrender.
那它现在是谁的
Then whose is she?
-一个车尾人的  -车尾人是什么
- A Tailie's. - And what is a Tailie?
我什么都不会给你的  不管你如何惩罚我
I won't give you anything no matter what you do to me,
我知道你想折磨我
and I know you want me to suffer.
但你再也伤害不了我了
You can't hurt me anymore, not really.
你好  梅兰妮
Hello, Melanie.
艾莉克斯
Alex.
你...你还活着
You're--you're alive.
见到你我无动于衷
I am distinctly underwhelmed.
人生的重要时刻往往都是这样的
Life's big moments are often like that.
不管他对你说了什么  都不是真的
Whatever he told you, it isn't true.
你偷走了一辆列车  然后你离开了我
You stole a train, and then you left me.
哪句是假话了
What's not true about that?
不  我派人去找过你
No, I sent people for you.
你  还有外公外婆
For you--for you and for Grandma and Grandpa,
但那些人没回来
but they never came back.
我一直在等你
I was waiting for you.
但从我手中偷走未来
But stealing the future from me
更加重要  不是吗
was more important, wasn't it?
艾莉克斯  求你
Alex, please.
我有太多话想说了
There's--there's too much to say.
是啊  快转移话题吧
God, yes, change the subject.
他们那边陷入了一片混乱
Their society is in shambles up there,
但农业区正常工作
but Ag-Sec is working.
太好了
Oh, good.
家禽  鸡蛋
Poultry, eggs.
头等厢就餐并没消失
First-class dining hasn't derailed off a cliff.
他们没有吗啡了
They were out of morphine...
我也没看见有马靴
And I didn't see any Jackboots.
之前一定很痛苦
Must have been painful.
你知道车尾人是什么吗
You know what a Tailie is?
不  但一个叫莱顿的男人似乎是管事的
No, but a man named Layton appears to be in charge,
和他一起的应该还有席司闸罗切
along with who I assume is Lead Brakeman Roche
以及乘客服务部那个金发妞
and the blonde from Hospitality.
没听说过莱顿先生这个人
Hmm, never heard of a Mr. Layton.
显然你妈妈一直在那边假冒我
Apparently your mother's been impersonating me up there.
他们想我了吗
Do they miss me?
乘客服务部还穿着制服
Well, the Hospitality's still in uniform.
奥德丽小姐
Miss Audrey...
还在
Still with us.
大家好
Hello.
-大家相处得还好吗  -不好
- Is everyone getting along? - No.
-带梅兰妮去禁闭室  -好的  女士
- Take Melanie to the brig. - Yes, ma'am.
看看我  亲爱的
Look at me, honey.
冷静  别让事情变得更糟了
Calmly now. Don't make it worse.
安静  请安静
Please, please!
没错  我们完全掌握了工程部
Yes, we have full engineering control,
但大爱丽丝就像锚一样控制着我们的速度
but Big Alice is like an anchor controlling our speed.
补给列车  能容纳多少工作人员  60人吗
The supply train, that's built for a crew of what, 60?
差不多吧  但无法获知
Give or take, but there's no way
列车被改装成什么样了
for us to know how she's been retrofitted.
好吧  那最多能容纳多少人
All right, what's her maximum crew size?
-猜猜  -猜吗
- Guess. - Guess?
200人  但或许更少
200, but probably less,
我们的工程师是他们的囚犯
and our Engineer is their prisoner.
乘客厌倦了战争
The passengers are tired of war.
我说错了吗
Am I wrong?
她一点没错
She's clearly not wrong.
大家都精疲力竭  我们需要休整
Everyone's exhausted. We need to recover.
他们还没进攻  对吧
They haven't invaded, have they?
那我们就先冷静一下
So let's just have a cooling-off period.
拜托  跟他展开对话
Please, yes, open talks with him.
梅兰妮现在或许就在那儿
Melanie's probably back there right now
跟威尔福德先生和她女儿谈判呢
working things out with Mr. Wilford and her daughter.
威尔福德先生
Mr. Wilford...
不只是想控制这趟列车
doesn't just want control of his train.
他想控制你们所有人  身体和灵魂
He wants control of all of you, body and soul.
没错  别相信他
That's right, don't trust him!
都安静
Hey, quiet down.
安静
Quiet!
40节车厢的寄生列车说了不算
A 40-car parasite does not call the shots around here.
雪国列车说了才算
Snowpiercer does!
听着  我们先按兵不动
All right, we hold fast.
叫它冷静期或什么都行  露丝
Call it a cooling off if you want to, Ruth,
但除非威尔福德交出梅兰妮  否则我们不谈
but we do not start talks until Wilford turns over Melanie.
好了  大家都听到了
All right, you heard the man.
我们的第一要务  我们的责任
Our first priority, our responsibility,
是让雪国列车保持稳定  大家吃饱  团结统一
is to keep Snowpiercer calm and fed and united,
跟以前一样
same as it ever was.
我们快速悄声地集结一支军队
Let's get a force together quickly, quietly.
-别让露丝知道  -不行  我们不能攻击他们
- Keep Ruth out of it. - No, we can't attack them.
我们完全不知道门背后是什么
We basically have no idea what's behind that door.
那梅兰妮怎么办
What about Melanie?
梅兰妮正是我们必须这么做的原因
Melanie is the reason we have to do this.
听着  我知道大家都疲惫不堪
Okay, look, I know everyone is tired,
但威尔福德有计划
but Wilford's got a plan.
我们得在他攻击我们前先出手
We need to hit him before he hits us.
瞧瞧是谁
Look who it is.
你这是要去哪呢
Whoa, whoa, where you think you're going?
-别碰我  -不然呢
- Don't touch me. - Yeah, or what?
提醒一句  莱顿先生
Just a warning, Mr. Layton,
-你的后院要起火了  -该死
- your laundry's about to flap. - Shit.
够了
That's enough.
不不  你哪儿都不能去
No, no, you're not going anywhere.
喂喂  后退  别这样
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey. Back up. Come on.
终极破坏者  大力士  你们怎么回事
Z-Wreck, Strong Boy, what's wrong with you?
莱顿  她出卖了乔茜
Layton, she sold out Josie.
怎么  在你的新列车上她不用为此付出代价吗
What, she don't gotta pay for that on your new train?
那是因为梅兰妮威胁她了  好吗
Look, Melanie was threatening her, okay?
而她屈服了  结果乔茜死了
And she cracked. Now Josie's dead.
我怀孕了  懂吗
I'm pregnant, all right?
是真的吗
Is that true?
扎拉
Zarah?
是真的
Yes, it is.
在雪国列车上怀孕
A pregnancy on Snowpiercer.
这是希望
It's hope.
梅兰妮之前威胁我们的孩子
Melanie was threatening our child.
你的孩子
Your child?
天呐  这消息足够改变一切
Oh, my goodness, this changes everything.
好了  你们两个  快走
All right, you two, go on, shove off.
-别纠缠这个女人了  -什么  我们还要...
- Leave the woman alone. - What? No, we still got--
你们在哪个过道睡觉就回哪去
Back to whatever hallway where you're sleeping in.
这不公平
This ain't right.
我跟你说  莱顿
Let me tell you something, Layton.
你的这些私事
All this personal shit,
都不会让你口中的民主更有说服力
it ain't making your democracy any easier to believe in.
你不能待在链条  扎拉
So you can't stay in The Chains, Zarah.
有孕在身  她可能会成为活靶子
Carrying your child, she might be a target.
我会去前列车厢帮你找个地儿
I will find somewhere for you uptrain
远离所有骚乱  好吗
away from all the ruckus, okay?
我们真的得向乘客发表讲话了
Now, we really must address the passengers.
我站在雪国列车一边  莱顿先生
I am on the side of Snowpiercer, Mr. Layton.
我和你一样  为所有乘客工作
I work for the passengers, just like you.
很好
Good.
说出你的真相吧
Well, speak your truth.
他们似乎是因此才相信的你
That's how they seem to trust you.
雪国列车上的公民们
Citizens of Snowpiercer,
经过漫长的七年
it took us seven long years
我们终于摆脱了威尔福德的阶级体制
to cast off Wilford's class system,
如今他已归来  并依附在了车尾
and now the man is back and latched on to The Tail.
他也愿意停车让我们挨冻
We know he is willing to stop us cold,
但司闸员和叛军
but Brakemen and the rebel army
控制住了新边境
have control of the new border.
露丝·沃德尔和乘客服务部
Ruth Wardell and Hospitality
将领导外交倡议
will lead diplomatic initiatives,
雪国列车也会采取一切必要途径
and Snowpiercer will use all means necessary
捍卫我们赢得的自由
to defend the liberties we've won.
但是
But...
尽管我们牺牲惨重
With everything we have sacrificed,
我还是非常遗憾
it is my great regret
也极为不情愿地
and my reluctant duty
暂时搁置为我们的民主实验
to put our democratic experiment on hold
在另行通知前  持续戒严
and to extend martial law until further notice.
我不够格的勇士朋友们
That, my half-ass warrior friends,
这意味着接下来还有麻烦
means trouble comes.
这么说肯定得不到人心
That will not be popular.
他有得选吗
What choice does he have?
管道工人争取的是投票权
Tunnelmen fought for a vote.
我们这会应该撰写《宪法》
We're supposed to be writing a constitution.
杰克斯  我也很想现在准备选举
Jakes, I wish we were preparing for elections too,
但革命尚未成功  我们仍需努力
but there's a few more miles to go.
我们还会号召你的协会加入  好吗
We're calling on your guild again, okay?
外面是什么样的
What's it like outside?
不要一下子就把气氛弄尴尬  好吗
Don't get immediately weird, okay?
我就是有几个问题
I just have some questions.
好的
Yeah, okay.
外面是什么样
Um, what's it like outside?
很冷
Um, it's chilly.
很吓人
It's horrifying.
还很伤感
And it's really sad
想到几年前还是一片生机勃勃
to think about everything that lived only a few years ago.
线虫就能存活
Nematodes will survive.
没错  线虫能存活
Yeah. Yeah, nematodes will.
你被冻伤了吗
Are you frostbit?
有点  不过没事  防护服被划破了
A little bit, but it's fine. Just broke the seal on my suit.
我的记忆越来越模糊了
I remember less and less of it--
关于旧世界的
the old world.
真可惜
That's a shame.
很抱歉你没能多体验那个世界
I'm sorry you couldn't spend more time in it.
列车就是我们现在的世界  我们能控制它
The train is our world now. We can control this.
怎么
What?
外公外婆最后怎么了
What happened with Grandma and Grandpa?
他们不愿跟你派来的人一起离开
They wouldn't leave with the men that you sent.
他们想死在家中
They wanted to die at home.
他们说我应该走  但我不想离他们而去
They said I should go, but I didn't wanna leave them.
你知道
You know...
我把你送走  和他们一起生活  是有原因的
I sent you away to live with them for a reason.
什么原因
Why?
因为你要去偷一辆火车
Because you had a train to steal
所以你不再需要一个女儿了
so you didn't need a daughter anymore?
为了让你远离他
To keep you from him.
你抛弃我之后  是他救了我
He's the one who saved me after you left me.
那不是他救你的原因
That's not why he saved you.
这是什么  在你防护服里发现的
What is this? It was in your suit.
这是一个雪样本
It's a snow sample.
你为什么要采集一个雪样本
Well, why'd you take a snow sample?
因为我已经七年没离开过雪国列车了
Because I haven't been off Snowpiercer in seven years.
你又在对我撒谎
You are lying to me again.
露丝  她不能来头等厢
Ruth, she can't be up here in First.
-为什么不能  -别这样  扎拉
- Why not? - Come on, Zarah.
这看上去像什么样子
How's it look?
我不在乎像什么样子  我只在乎我的宝宝
I don't care how it looks. I care about the baby.
莱顿先生  你会需要一块地方
You are going to need a place, Mr. Layton,
一个处理日常行政事务的基地
a base of operations for day-to-day administration.
这整层空间都为你所用
You can use this whole floor.
楼上有单独的卧室
There are separate accommodations upstairs.
在雪国列车上  怀孕是有特权的
Pregnancy comes with privilege on Snowpiercer.
我们不知道该如何感谢你  露丝
We don't know how to thank you, Ruth.
我不知道你是如何办到这些的
I don't know how you pulled this off.
如今人人都在破坏规则
Well, everyone's bending rules these days,
不是吗  莱顿先生
aren't they, Mr. Layton?
这里的原时髦主人哪去了
What happened to the chic owners?
这本是施瓦兹的车厢  他们八十来岁了
It was the Schwartz Car. They were in their 80s.
他们在车尾部队夺取列车的早晨就服用了氰化物
They took cyanide the morning the Tailie army took the train,
所以让这里重获点欢乐的气息  不是很好吗
so it would be nice to let some joy back in, wouldn't it, hmm?
再多一个到处乱跑的小宝宝
With a little 'un running around?
两个安保芯片
Two security chips.
你的钥匙  不用谢
Your door keys. You're welcome.
‎数学不过关 你就有麻烦
-兰迪
‎努力
荣誉
恐惧
‎努力
荣誉
恐惧
‎努力
荣誉
恐惧
‎努力
荣誉
恐惧
‎努力
荣誉
恐惧
‎努力
荣誉
恐惧
‎努力
荣誉
恐惧
‎努力
荣誉
恐惧
‎努力
荣誉
恐惧
‎努力
荣誉
恐惧
‎努力
荣誉
恐惧
‎努力
荣誉
恐惧
‎努力
荣誉
恐惧
‎努力
荣誉
恐惧
‎努力
荣誉
恐惧
‎努力
荣誉
恐惧
‎努力
荣誉
恐惧
‎努力
荣誉
恐惧
‎努力
荣誉
恐惧
‎努力
荣誉
恐惧
‎努力
荣誉
恐惧
‎努力
荣誉
恐惧
‎努力
荣誉
恐惧
‎努力
荣誉
恐惧
‎努力
荣誉
恐惧
‎努力
荣誉
恐惧
‎努力
荣誉
恐惧
‎努力
荣誉
恐惧
‎努力
荣誉
恐惧
‎努力
荣誉
恐惧
‎努力
荣誉
恐惧
‎努力
荣誉
恐惧
‎努力
荣誉
恐惧
‎努力
荣誉
恐惧
‎努力
荣誉
恐惧
‎努力
荣誉
恐惧
‎努力
荣誉
恐惧
‎努力
荣誉
恐惧
‎努力
荣誉
恐惧
‎努力
荣誉
恐惧
‎努力
荣誉
恐惧
‎努力
荣誉
恐惧
‎努力
荣誉
恐惧
‎努力
荣誉
恐惧
转过去
Turn around.
把手背到背后
Hands behind your back.
-是她  -是的  没错
- It is her. - Yes, it is.
正是她
The very one.
不是什么戴着头套的人
Not someone else with a bag on her head.
好样的
Good job, that.
确实很棒
Good job indeed.
卡维尔夫人本人
Ms. Cavill herself.
我记得你们  你们是那对医生
And I remember you. You're the doctors.
海德伍德
Headwood.
海德伍德夫妇
Headwoods.
你们把这里都改进了
You retrofitted all this in here?
来吧
Come.
看吧  她在打量这里
You see? She's angling.
已经喜欢上这里了  不是吗
Digging already, isn't she?
不过我们很警觉
But we're on our toes.
-警觉  -来  坐下
- Toes. - Come, sit.
脚趾
外面可真冷啊
Bloody cold outside.
是不是被冻伤了
Did Jack Frost get a few nips in?
我的肩膀
My shoulder.
是的  一只小鸟告诉我们你的肺也受伤了
Yes, a little bird told us you've been lung-nipped too.
是艾莉克斯说的
Alex?
让我们来看一下
Let's take a look.
张嘴
Open.
好吧  这里有点状况
Ah, okay. There's a bit of business.
很好
Lovely.
-真熟练  -很好
- Crafty. - Lovely
请咳两下
Cough, please.
吸气
Inhale.
算你走运  我们通过治疗我们的人
Lucky for you, we've made several breakthroughs
取得了一些突破
treating our crew.
这  这是什么
What--what is that?
-我们是叫它黏糊糊  -我们叫它黏糊糊
- We just call it goop. - We call it goop.
人造组织凝胶
Synthetic tissue gel.
涂上就能缓和疼痛
Soothing to the touch.
没错  涂完之后
Yes, by the time we're finished,
你连疤都不会有
you won't even have a scar.
伏下
Get down.
有新鲜食物吗
Hey, got any fresh food?
取决于你有什么
Depends what you got.
好
Okay.
谁有水果
Who's got fruit?
谢谢
Thank you.
我们做交易
We make trade.
我们说英文  混蛋
We're speaking English, douchebag.
我有个多汁的苹果
Then me have a succulent apple,
一个佛罗里达有机橙子
an organic Floridian orange,
美味的块茎
and a-- gourmet tuber.
一包无限量的神奇爱丽丝大麻
One QP Amazing Alice.
排好队  排好队
You can get back in line. Get back in line.
大家都闭嘴
Everybody keep their mouths shut,
你们都能分到一份
and you'll all get a cut.
我终于来到车尾了
I finally made it to the actual Tail,
是真的  这里臭死了
and it's true. It stinks.
以前不是这样的
It ain't what it used to be like.
喂  列车疯子和无头苍蝇司闸员
Oi, Train Psycho and Brakeman Blowie.
你们不能再往前走
That's far enough right there.
我们只是想看看  现在可以随意走动
We're just having a look. It's an open train.
对你来说是戒严
It's martial law for you.
威尔福德先生
Mr. Wilford.
不管门后有什么
Whatever's beyond that door?
我认为大家机会平等
It's equal opportunity, I think.
威尔福德先生来了  威尔福德先生来了
Mr. Wilford's coming. Mr. Wilford's coming.
小莱
Hey, LJ!
这边请
This way.
她已经到了
Herself has arrived.
梅兰妮
Melanie.
别拘束  我只是在泡澡
Make yourself at home. I'm just having a wallow.
艾莉珊德拉为什么没和我们一起吃东西
Why isn't Alexandra eating with us?
多得是时间  梅兰妮
Plenty of time, Melanie.
多得是时间
Plenty of time.
我们已经做了决定
We've made the decision.
莱顿  这样对梅来说太冒险了
Layton, it's just so risky for Mel.
你想让梅兰妮回来吗
You wanna get Melanie back?
这是我们改变条件的方式
This is how we change the terms.
我会保持线路畅通
I'll keep the line open.
我们准备好了
Look, we're ready to go,
但是首先  我们要把门打开
but first, they gotta open the door.
我们不知道什么时候才能打开
We don't know when that's gonna be.
我不喜欢等他们行动
I hate waiting on their move.
你闻到了吗
Hey, you smell that?
谁在抽大麻
Who is smoking weed?
派克
Pike.
七年都没抽大麻卷烟了  兄弟
Seven years without a blunt, brother,
这种最棒了
and this is the kind.
才花了我们一个土豆而已
All it cost us was a fricking potato.
首先你要去禁闭室
First you're going to lockup.
不  等等  不  给  大麻都在这
No, wait, no, here, here, this is all of it.
-我发誓  -不不不
- I swear.- No, no, no, hey, hey, hey.
这是我们突袭的办法  来
This is how we get the jump on 'em. Come on.
快走
Move it.
太久了
It's taking way too long.
准备好了吗
You ready?
好了
Yeah.
40节车厢  我每天走400节
40 cars. I walk that 10 times a day.
你没准备好
You're not ready.
你还是个半吊子司闸员
You're still half Brakeman,
极度害怕那扇门后的情况
scared shitless of what's on the other side of that door.
如果你不能接受灭绝的事实
If you don't embrace extinction,
你就已经死了
you're already dead.
-准备好了吗  -准备好了
- You ready? - Yeah, I'm fine.
我有一个芒果  拿去交易
I got a mango. Take it to the deal, okay?
你们还有古典毒品吗
You got any other vintage drugs in there--
可卡因  乙醚
blow, ether?
我有一个芒果
I got a mango.
完美无暇
It's perfect.
很柔软
So soft.
可以说是鲜嫩多汁
Juice explosion, one might say.
剥开
Peel it back--
凯文  想要芒果吗
Well, Kevin? Want a mango?
要是他发现的话
If he ever found out...
你叫什么  朋友
Hey, what's your name, friend?
我叫派克  任您吩咐
My name's Pike. Anything you need...
拿上防护服
Grab the suit!
所有人快进去
Everyone in quick!
第二波
Second wave!
弩
Crossbows!
谢谢  赛克斯
Thank you, Sykes.
我为了这个麦芽酒绑架了一个酒馆老板
I essentially kidnapped a brewpub owner for this ale.
-你还记得吗  -我记得
- Do you remember? - I remember.
在得梅因
In Des Moines.
尝起来像他的酒
Tastes like his stuff.
我不会告诉你我们的酿酒师是谁
I'm not telling you who our brewer is.
见鬼
Drat.
火车头
Engine.
先生  雪国列车突破了门
Sir, Snowpiercer breached the door.
什么  他们怎么做到的
What? How the hell did they do that?
还不清楚  先生
It's unclear, sir.
派出鲍勃
Send in Bob.
-冷淡鲍勃还是油商鲍勃  -你说呢
- Icy Bob or Oiler Bob? - Who do you think?
-等等  -上  上
- Wait-- Go, go!
趴下  快走
Get down! Let's go!
退后  退后
Retreat! Fall back!
快来  快来
Come on, come on.
Come on! Come on.
快走
Let's go!
快  快
Keep moving. Come on!
过去
Get through!
他靠自己突破了那节车厢
He breached that car himself.
他一下就让温度降到了零下57度
He got it to 70 below in seconds,
而他毫无感觉
and he didn't even feel it.
-我去吧  -拿下他
- Hey, I got this. - Go get him.
有多少人受伤  20
How many injured, 20?
在一次我不知情的进攻中
In an attack that I wasn't informed of.
那是戒严下的一次军事决定
It was a military decision under martial law.
别往心里去
Don't take it personally.
我怎么能不往心里去
How can I not take it personally?
你通知了火车头但是没通知乘客服务部
You saw fit to inform the Engine but not Hospitality,
你还被打得落花流水  对吗
and you got your ass handed to you, didn't you?
我们没丢失任何领地  我们也拿到了我们想要的东西
We didn't lose any ground, and we got what we came for.
你朋友吗
Friend of yours?
凯文
Kevin.
天啊  露丝  你们都疯了
Good God, Ruth, you people have gone mad.
我  我能理解为什么看上去像这样  但是
I--well, I can see how it looks that way, but--
这是个错误
This is a big mistake.
威尔福德不在乎你的死活
Wilford doesn't care if you die,
或者农业区的死活
if Ag-Sec dies.
-他可以重新开始一切  -走
- He can restart everything. - Let's go.
坐下
Sit down.
人质是凯文  先生
The hostage is Kevin, sir.
真是无知和侮辱  竟然觉得
The utter ignorance, the insult to think
靠一个人质就能获得
that they could gain some kind of leverage
某种筹码
with a hostage...
交换你
for you.
我能说什么呢  他们在这方面是新人
What can I say? They're new at this.
你偷了我的列车
You stole my train!
用了我的名字
Used my name.
你自己到处都贴着
Well, you plastered it everywhere.
我创造了世界
I built the world!
只剩一个了  这是我的
It's the only one left, and it's mine!
我是老大
I run it.
你呢  你当时在爸爸的农场里修拖拉机
You, you were fixing tractors on Daddy's farm.
我在你17岁的时候把你从猪屎里捞出来
I lifted you out of pig shit at 17.
我分享一切
I shared everything.
我给了你一切
I gave you everything...
解决方案
the solution.
-没有解决方案...  -老天啊
- There's no solution... - Oh, for God's sake.
除非我们能出去
Until we can go back out there!
这就是世界
This is the world!
一辆在钢轨上呼啸的列车
A rolling steel artery on a dead marble.
过来  跟我过来
Come on. You come with me.
你是工程师
You're an Engineer.
工程师  让雪国列车完全停下来
Engineer, bring Snowpiercer to a full stop.
-完全停下来  乐意至极  -艾莉克斯
- Full stop, gladly. - Alex.
调头
Reverse.
他放下了锚
He's dropped the anchor.
‎紧急停车
不不不  我们不能停下  他会断开的
No, no, no, we can't stop. He'll disconnect.
‎紧急停车
我要夺回她  梅
I'm taking her back, Mel.
如果你不能让这个莱顿交出我的火车
If you can't get this Layton to surrender my train,
艾莉克斯就会断开列车
Alex will disconnect,
我们会反向旋转一圈
and we'll take a short spin in reverse.
等我们回来  他们都会死掉
When we return, they'll all be dead,
而你接下来几年的工作
and your job for the next several years
就是把他们都做成肥料
will be to compost every last one of them.
拜托  别生气
Come on! No hard feelings!
启动列车
Let's get moving!
断开雪国列车连接  以1/4速度反向行进
Disconnect Snowpiercer. Reverse 1/4 speed.
-不要这么做  -为什么
- Don't do it. - Why?
-这是命令  艾莉克斯  -因为这是对的
- It's an order, Alex. - Because it's right.
因为那辆车是我们的未来
Because that train is our future.
天啊
Oh, my God.
把威士忌给我  赶紧照做
Get me that whiskey. Just get it done!
如果你断开列车  那些人都会死
If you disconnect, all of those people will die.
整个世界都会死
A whole world will die.
相信我
Believe me,
你不想背上这种良心债的
you don't want that on your conscience.
赶紧断开  艾莉克斯
Disconnect now, Alex.
快点
Come on, now.
艾莉克斯  没事的
Alex, it's all right.
错误的选择  亲爱的
Wrong choice, honey.
我无法断开
I can't disconnect.
你做了什么
What have you done?
他覆盖了连接机制
He overbuilt the connecting mechanism.
我那次就说了  还记得吗
I said so at the time, remember?
我说过如果中央锁
I told you if something goes wrong
有什么问题  你就不可能
with that central lock, you'll never be able
手动解除机械臂
to manually undo the grappling arms.
天啊  我们现在被困在这里了
Holy shit. We're stuck together.
我们永远...都困在这里了
Here we are--permanently.
所以你最好给艾莉克斯下达命令
So you better give Alex the order to get Snowpiercer
重新发动雪国列车  不然我们过几分钟都会死
moving again or we'll all die in a few minutes.
不可能
Never.
这其实是唯一的解决办法
It's kind of the only solution, really.
我们只是得想办法合作
We just have to find a way to work together.
你中了她的招  达布斯
She got you, Dubs.
-闭嘴  -真的没有别的选择了
- Shut up. - Really don't have a choice.
等待...  命令
Wait...for the order.
谢天谢地
Oh, thank God.
我们得救了
We're spared.
他放过了我们  他放过了我们
He spared us. He spared us.
这将是一场漫长的冷战
This gonna be a long cold war.